Guide to the United States, Confederate States, and foreign currency collection 1974.120
Brooklyn Historical Society
United States, Confederate States, and foreign currency collection
1690-1904
1775-1865
Brooklyn Historical Society
Huntington, Edna
1974.120
2.54 Linear Feet in one manuscript box and one oversize box.
This collection contains bank notes, fractional currency, postage stamps, and treasury notes, most of which were printed in the United States. Also included are various forms of paper currency printed by the Confederate States of America during the Civil War, as well as currency printed by various foreign countries, such as Brazil, China, Dominican Republic, and Japan. Two bound volumes containing historical sketches of paper money printed in the continental United States and the State of Pennsylvania are also included.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Fred T. Aldridge, 1891; Burt P. Greenman, date unknown; Charles Hallock, date unknown; J.S. Hicks, date unknown; John A. King, 1898; William Cary Langer, date unknown; Daniel Church McEwen, 1898; William Miles, date unknown; the North Carolina Historical Commission, date unknown; James L. Phelps, Jr., 1870; John P. Rolfe, date unknown; Reuben W. Ropes, date unknown; N.H.T. Squires, date unknown; B.C. Weekes, 1921; Julius Wilcox, 1890; and H.F. Wing, date unknown. J. H. Walters, October 1948. Collection formally accessioned in 1974.
Volume of United States Fractional Currency compiled by the Long Island Historical Society transferred from uncataloged books in CBH's Library.
Arrangement
Collection assembled in 1936 from various donations. Materials are generally arranged by category.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains bank notes, fractional currency, postage stamps, and treasury notes printed in the State of New York and various other American states during the period 1690 to 1904, with the bulk dating from 1775 to 1865. Also included are various forms of paper currency printed by the Confederate States of America during the Civil War, as well as currency printed by various foreign countries, such as Brazil, China, Dominican Republic, and Japan. Two bound volumes containing historical sketches of paper money printed in the continental United States and the State of Pennsylvania are also included.
Language of Materials
Materials primarily in English, with some materials in Japanese, Spanish, and Chinese.
National bank notes; Paper money; Postage stamps; Money |z Dominican Republic; Money |z Japan; Money |z China; Money |z Brazil; Money |z Confederate States of America; Money |z United States; Money |z United States |x History |y Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775; Money |z United States |x History |y Revolution, 1775-1783; Money |z United States |x History |y Civil War, 1861-1865; Money |z Pennsylvania; Money |z New York (State); Money |z United States |x History |y 1783-1865; Money -- Rhode Island; Money -- South Carolina; Money -- Georgia; Money -- Massachusetts; Money -- New Jersey; Money -- Connecticut
- [United States currency], 1776-1789 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- [American British colonies currency], 1759-1776 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Continental currency, 1776-1779 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- An historical sketch of the paper money issued by Pennsylvania, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Foreign currency, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bank notes, 1800-1864 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Fractional currency, 1862-1863 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Confederate currency, 1862-1865 (Box 1, Folder 8, Oversize OS-36)
- Historical sketch of continental paper money book, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- [News clipping regarding fractional currency], 1904 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- [Certificates], 1795-1866 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- United States Fractional Currency, 1862-1868 (Oversize OS-36)
  Scope and Contents
  This file contains a bound volume of United States fractional currency pasted into the pages. The volume was compiled by the Long Island Historical Society.